Robert Raimon Papers /3036
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Robert Raimon Papers
1920-1958
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Raimon, Robert
/3036
4 cubic feet
4 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
Papers mostly concerning research in railroad labor, specifically the Chesapeake and Ohio Railway (C&O).
3074160
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, March 23, 2015
EAD encoding:
Elizabeth Parker, October 11, 2022
Biographical / Historical
Robert Raimon (September 29, 1923 August 31, 1995) was professor of labor economics at Cornell University's School of Industrial and Labor Relations.
A veteran of World War II, Raimon completed his undergraduate degree from Columbia University in 1947. He earned his PhD from Cornell's School of Industrial and Labor Relations in 1951 and joined the faculty as an assistant professor in the same year. In 1974, Professor Raimon retired from the faculty and was appointed professor emeritus. In retirement and until 1989, Raimon served on the editorial board of the Industrial and Labor Relations Review.
See the Cornell University Faculty Memorial Statement for Professor Robert Raimon: http://hdl.handle.net/1813/18596
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1945 as the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, the ILR School today is advancing the world of work through teaching, research and outreach. ILR's mission is to prepare leaders, inform national and international employment and labor policy, and improve working lives, but as the world of work evolves, the school's focus broadens to keep pace with that change.
ILR studies many areas that shape the working world and contribute to an organization's success in a global economy. These include human resource management; labor-management relations; labor economics; organizational behavior; international and comparative labor; labor relations, labor law and history; conflict resolution; management development; diversity management; employment and disability; and social statistics.
An ILR education is grounded in the social sciences. Students and faculty explore and gain an understanding of human behavior through the lens of the workplace. Students also learn how organizations work and how they fit into the larger society and economy. As a result, they acquire knowledge and skills that help them to solve problems on-the-job and to build and manage productive work relationships. An ILR education, for students and professionals, is practical and applied.
ILR has more full-time faculty involved in teaching and research that spans the broad range of work and employment disciplines than any other educational institution of its kind. Its Martin P. Catherwood Library is regarded as the most comprehensive source of information in North America on work, employment and labor issues.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /3007: Maurice Neufeld Papers /4004: ILR School Librarian's Office Files /4135 OHT: ILR School Founding Faculty Oral History Project /4297: ILR School Biography Files 6021/008: Theodore W. Kheel Books and Articles
Wages -- United States; Raimon, Robert Leonard,1923-; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations --Faculty.
3074160
- Group B-26 A School Research; Robert Raimon (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  5x8 index cards
- Record Group B-26 A School Research: Rob Raimon (Box 2, Folder 1)
  notes on Wage Theory Study; 5x8 index cards
- Miscellaneous Items, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Additions to Strengthening C O, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- American Airlines Job Evaluation (Box 3, Folder 3)
- American Short Line data on subordinate officials and RIA (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Automation Harrison Remarks (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Attorney General Statement on National Mediation Board, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Brotherhood of Railway Clerks (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Bambert Letters (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Brotherhood of Railway Clerks Bulletin (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Biblio - Items to Process (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Bibliography or Items Processed (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Bureau of Information of Eastern Railways (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Railroads - Business Week Report (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Chesapeake Ohio R. R. Annual Report, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Clerks Convention Proceedings (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Canadian Sources (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Chrysler Auto Data, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Chrysler Criteria of Management, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Collective Agreements (Box 3, Folder 19)
  C O
- C O Agreements (Box 3, Folder 20)
- C O Certification (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Clerks Case (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Moore Summary of Union Case, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- C O Collective Agreement Exclusion Clauses (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Computer Literature (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Computer Technical Data (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Notes on 1950 Congressional Hearing (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Cornell School of Business Management Development Program Outline (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Criteria of Management C O, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Crypt II Items (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Cusik - "Why Must a Railroad Grow?" (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Cullen Comments on MS (Box 3, Folder 32)
- 1919 and 1943 Document References (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Dale of Outline of Criteria, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- C O Decline of Supervisory Union Membership (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Interview with Mr. Di Pasquale, Director of Labor Relations, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  American Airlines
- Executive Compensation, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- FLSA Bulletin Notes (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Featherbedding (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Financial Reports: C O, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- C O FLSA (Box 3, Folder 41)
- FLSA official pamphlets (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Footnotes to First Bibliography of MS (Box 3, Folder 43)
- 1/2 Sheet Footnotes to RLA (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Ford Foundation Speech on Transportation, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- GE Conference - Drucker Others on Management (Box 3, Folder 46)
- General Foods - Job Evaluation for Management Scheme (Box 3, Folder 47)
- General Foods Statement of Evaluating Statement Jobs (Box 3, Folder 48)
- GM-UAW RE: Management Right RE: Technological Change (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Government Proposals for Revision of ICC Non-labor practices (Box 3, Folder 50)
- C O Growth of Technical and Allied Management (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Gulf Project - Cual, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Harrison (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Harrison - On 1958 Law Changes (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Hook Jr. data from ILR Library (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Interstate Commerce Comm., 1958 (Box 3, Folder 56)
- ICC Cases- Eastern Railway Mimeo Cases (Box 3, Folder 57)
- ICC Chairman Biography NYT, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 58)
- ICC Cases (Box 3, Folder 59)
- ICC Ex. Parte No. 72 etc. (Box 3, Folder 60)
- ICC - Ex Parte 72, RIR's cases (Box 3, Folder 61)
- C O Intra-Union Aspects (Box 3, Folder 62)
- Investors railroads noted guide sheets (Box 3, Folder 63)
- Job Evaluation - Printed Items (Box 3, Folder 64)
- Job Evaluation - Typed Items (Box 3, Folder 65)
- Kaltenborn on Representation in Railroads (Box 3, Folder 66)
- Landsberger on Hoselitz-Atkinson MS (Box 3, Folder 67)
- Layoff Procedures (Box 3, Folder 68)
- "Man Hunt for Top Executives" (Box 3, Folder 69)
  Robert N. McMurry
- Extra Paper for MS Revision (Box 3, Folder 70)
- Persons to See RIA Copy (Box 3, Folder 71)
- MS on RLA: Ramon and Dale (Box 3, Folder 72)
- MS on RLA pre-final draft (Box 3, Folder 73)
- Manuscript Final Draft (Box 3, Folder 74)
- Rejected - 1 (Box 3, Folder 75)
- Unfair Labor Practice (Box 3, Folder 76)
- Some Other (non rep) Ambiguities and Failures of RIA (Box 3, Folder 77)
- Processed - 1 (Box 3, Folder 78)
- Processed - 2 (Box 3, Folder 79)
- Conclusion Notes for Manuscript (Box 3, Folder 80)
- Manuscript - 1st Draft (Box 3, Folder 81)
- Stocks (Box 3, Folder 82)
- Social Insurance (Box 3, Folder 83)
- Miscellaneous Items for Possible Inclusion to Manuscript or Relevant to its Revision (Box 3, Folder 84)
- NRAB Items (Box 3, Folder 85)
- NMB Combined Functions (Box 3, Folder 86)
- Miscellaneous Manuscript (Box 3, Folder 87)
- C O - Taft-Hartley, TH Hearings, and Allied Data But Not Testimonies (Box 4, Folder 1)
- C O Testimonies (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Time Magazine - "The New Age of Railroads" (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Unions, Subordinate Officials Letters (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Richberg in Union Shop in Railroads (Box 4, Folder 5)
- USRRBd Reproduction of ICC, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Unconstitutionality Issue Re-RIA (Box 4, Folder 7)
- C O Union Discipline Over Management Issues (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Union Shop Hearings - Emergency Board, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Union Shop on Railroads (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Motormen Pay $24 a week or $8910 a year (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Yale Club (Box 4, Folder 12)
  1925-1926 data
- 26 Management Re: Sub Officials (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Maintenance of Way, RR Notes, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Work Load Issue (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Railway Age Interview (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Revelations re RLA, 1925-1926 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Biblio References on RLA (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Labor Relations Personnel Research Unit (Box 4, Folder 19)
- RR - "Rails Thrive - Their Stocks Sag", 1957 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- C O Railway Biblio (Box 4, Folder 21)
- RR Statement of the Imaginary Union Case (Box 4, Folder 22)
- C O - Recruitment of College Personnel (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Recruitment of Management Advise Effect on Unionism (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Reference to Salary Stabilization Board of the Korean Period (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Representation in the Railroad Industry by Jacob J. Kaufman (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Staff Personnel Trends (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Statistical Railroad Airline Data (Box 4, Folder 28)
- C O Slichter, Spohn, and Calkins Panel (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Stever, Marian-Wage Structure of Class 1 Railroad (Box 4, Folder 30)
- C O Strategy (Box 4, Folder 31)
- C O Strategy Schedule, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- C O - Public Policy Chapter (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Passenger Traffic Data (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Patton - "Executive Compensation" (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Pax Data (Box 4, Folder 36)
- C O - Productivity (Box 4, Folder 37)
- C O - Productivity Data, 1935-1955 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Professionals - Shortages, issue of unionisms, etc. (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Permission to Quote Items (Box 4, Folder 40)
- NMB Cases (Box 4, Folder 41)
- NLRB Decisions Re: Supervisors (Box 4, Folder 42)
- BNA Fringe Group Treatment Under NLRA (Box 4, Folder 43)
- C O - National Mediation Board Cases and Precedents (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Rules and Regulations of NMB (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Department of Craft and Class Volume Notes (Box 4, Folder 46)
- The Need for Criteria In Arguing the Scope Rule (Box 4, Folder 47)
- New Investment, Railroads, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Notes on the Structuring of a C O Approach to the Demand of the Clerks for Unionization of the Computer Staff (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Northwest Airlines Agreement (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Management Criteria, Job Evaluation, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 51)
- Management Development C O Project, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 52)
- Management Document - Overall view of the case (Box 4, Folder 53)
- Management Development - Finance Department, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 54)
- C O Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 55)
- Further Research Items (Box 4, Folder 56)
- Moore, Bryant, and Bambert, etc. (Box 4, Folder 57)
  Correspondence
- J. R. Morris - "Repeal of the Railway Right-to-Work Law" (Box 4, Folder 58)
  an appraisal
- MS - Processed Items (Box 4, Folder 59)